Trades Union Congress (Great Britain) Pamphlets 5338
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Trades Union Congress (Great Britain) Pamphlets
1924-1967
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Trades Union Congress (Great Britain)
5338
0.5 cubic feet
0.5 linear ft.
Pamphlets, publications.
Publications of the Trades Union Congress of Great Britain.
5975944
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
R. Miles, November 15, 2013
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 30, 2015
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of publications of the Trades Union Congress of Great Britain. They are arranged alphabetically by topic.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Trades Union Congress.
5975944
- Education (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Item 1: Education and Democracy: TUC Aspirations and Activities (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Scope and Contents
    Author: Trades Union Congress (TUC)
    Format: Publication
    Language: English.
  - Item 2: Education of Children Over Eleven (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Notes: Labour's Recommendations for Development and Improvement
  - Item 3: School Desks Are Too Small These Days, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Author: Labour Party
    Notes: Leaflet no.5
  - Item 4: Staffin in Public Elementary Schools, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Author: Barbara Drake; R. H. Tawney
  - Item 5: T.U.C. Summer School, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    Notes: July 11-25, 1931. Ruskin College, Oxford
- Fascism (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Item 1: Austrian Democracy Under Fire, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Author: Otto Bauer
  - Item 2: Hitlerism: Down With Fascism, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Author: Joseph Compton; Walter M. Citrine
  - Item 3: The Menace of Dictatorship, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Author: Walter M. Citrine; T. Mycock; Aneurin Bevan; E. J. Evans; C. G. Blanchard; T. Scollan; A. G. Tompkins
  - Item 4: Peace or War?, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Author: Walter M. Citrine
    Notes: Full Report of the momentous debate at the Margate Trades Union Congress on the present International Crisis.
  - Item 5: The Spanish Problem, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Notes: Report of Speeches at the Plymouth Trade Union Congress
  - Item 6: Under the Heel of Hitler: The Dictatorship Over Sport in Nazi Germany, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- General strike, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Item 1: News Bulletin, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Notes: May 6, 1926.
  - Item 2: The Newspaper World, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Notes: May 22, 1926. Complete issue.
  - Item 3: The Newspaper World, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Notes: May 29, 1926. Single page.
  - Item 4: The Newspaper World, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Notes: June 5, 1926. Single page.
  - Item 5: Punch, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Notes: May 12, 1926. Complete issue.
  - Item 6: Punch, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Notes: May 19, 1926. Complete issue.
  - Item 7: Radio News Bulletin, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Notes: May 11, 1926. Bulletin no.3
  - Item 8: British Gazette, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Notes: May 6, 1926. Newspaper
  - Item 9: British Gazette, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Notes: May 7, 1926. Newspaper
  - Item 10: A Souvenir of the General Strike, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Notes: The British Gazette Complete reproduction in miniature
  - Item 11: The Castle Strike Bulletin, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Notes: no.2 (1926:May 12)
  - Item 12: Daily Graphic, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Notes: May 8, 1926.
  - Item 13: Daily Mirror, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Notes: Strike Bulletin no.4 (1926:May 8)
  - Item 14: The Daily Telegraph, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Notes: May 10, 1926. Fourth Strike Issue
  - Item 15: Food Supplies, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Notes: "Sanctioned to Work" Placard
  - Item 16: Foyles News Bulletin, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Author: G. Foyles; W. Foyles
    Notes: no.1 (1926:May 5)
  - Item 17: Latest News Bulletin, 1926 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    Author: G. Saunders
    Notes: no.11 (1926:May 10)
- Health (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Item 1: Dermatitis, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Item 2: John Smith Has an Accident: A Case for Workmen's Compensation, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Item 3: The Labour Movement and the Hospital Crisis: A Statement of Policy with Regard to Hospitals (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Item 4: Social Insurance and Trade Union Membership (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Industrial News, 1937-1938 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Item 1: Industrial News: For the Use of the Press, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Notes: no.504 (1937:Jan. 19)
  - Item 2: Industrial News: For the Use of the Press, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Notes: no.505 (1937:Feb. 2)
  - Item 3: Industrial News: For the Use of the Press, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Notes: no.507 (1937:Mar. 2)
  - Item 4: Industrial News: For the Use of the Press, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Notes: no.509 (1937:Apr. 6)
  - Item 5: Industrial News: For the Use of the Press, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Notes: no.510 (1937:Apr. 20)
  - Item 6: Industrial News: For the Use of the Press, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Notes: no.520 (1937:Sep. 14)
  - Item 7: Industrial News: For the Use of the Press, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Notes: no.527 (1937:Dec. 21)
  - Item 8: Industrial News: For the Use of the Press, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Notes: no.536 (1938:Apr. 26)
- Mining (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Item 1: Coal: The Labour Plan (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Item 2: Coal and Commonsense: Labour's Scheme for the Future of the Coal Industry, 1925 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Author: Herbert Smith; A. J. Cook
  - Item 3: The Mining Dispute: Miners' Wages Protected, A Lesson in Trade Union Unity (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Author: Herbert Smith
  - Item 4: The Mining Dispute: Miners' Wages Protected, A Lesson in Trade Union Unity (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Notes: Copy 2.
  - Item 5: The Mining Situation: An Immediate Programme (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Item 6: The Mining Situation: An Immediate Programme (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Item 7: The Mining Situation: An Immediate Programme (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Notes: Copy 3.
  - Item 8: The Truth About the Notts Miners' Ballot: An Answer to Critics, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    Notes: Campaign for freedom and Fair Play
- Politics (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Item 1: Labour and the Nation: Supplement on Banking and Currency Policy, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Author: J. Ramsay MacDonald
  - Item 2: Reminder, It's Polling Day, Have You Voted Yet? (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Notes: Leaflet no.9
  - Item 3: The Trade Unions and the National Financial Situation: Discussion at the Bristol Trades Union Congress., 1931 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Author: Ernest Bevin; Arthur Hayday; A. J. Cook; Walter M. Citrine
  - Item 4: Labour and the Empire: Africa (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Author: J. H. Thomas
  - Item 5: Labour and the Nation, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Notes: Revised edition
  - Item 6: Labour and the Nation, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Notes: Revised edition. Copy 2.
- Productivity (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Item 1: Trade Unions and Productivity (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Author: Vincent Tewson
    Notes: Report and Recommendations of a team of British Trade Union Officials
  - Item 2: Trade Unions and Productivity (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Notes: Report and Recommendations of a team of British Trade Union Officials. Copy 2.
  - Item 3: The Waste of Capitalism, 1924 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Author: A. A. Purcell
- Reports (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Item 1: Final Report, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Author: Arthur Hayday; Melchett
    Notes: Conference on Industrial Reorganisation and Industrial Relations
  - Item 2: Industrial Conference Report, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Item 3: Reportof the Seventh Annual Conference of Trades Councils, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    Notes: May 30, 1931.
  - Item 4: Trade Boards ane the Cave Report (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Trade (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Item 1: Commonwealth Trade: A New Policy, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Item 2: Commonwealth Trade: A New Policy, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Item 3: The Public Control and Regulation of Industry and Trade (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Notes: C. G. Report
  - Item 4: Tariffs and World Trade: An Examination of Our Fiscal Policy, 1932 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Notes: The TUC Report
- Trade Union Congress (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Item 1: The General Council of the Trades Union Congress: Its Powers, Functions, and Work (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Author: A. B. Swales
    Notes: Trades Unionism in Action, G. C. Pamphlet no.2
  - Item 2: The General Council of the Trades Union Congress: Its Powers, Functions, and Work (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Notes: Trades Unionism in Action, G. C. Pamphlet no.2. Copy 2.
  - Item 3: The Story of the Trades Union Congress (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Author: Fred Bramley
    Notes: Trades Unionism in Action, G. C. Pamphlet no.1.
  - Item 4: The Public Regulation of Industry and Trade, 1931 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Item 5: What the T.U.C. Is Doing, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Item 6: What the T.U.C. Is Doing, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Item 7: Irish Bulletin, 1921 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    Notes: Circular letter on contacting the publisher of the bulletin
- Unemployment (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Item 1: Administering Unemployment Insurance, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Notes: Report of the Trades Union Congress Deputation to the Minister of Labour
  - Item 2: The Government Evades Its National Responsibility: T.U.C. Criticism of the Unemployment Bill, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Item 3: Interm Joint Report on Unemployment, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Notes: March 12, 1929. Conference on Industrial Reorganisation and Industrial Relations
  - Item 4: Unemployment and the Cost of Livinf, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Unionism (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Item 1: Composite Resolution: Mond-Turner Conferences, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Author: A. G. Tomkins; J. T. Brownlie
  - Item 2: Congress Discusses Workers' Control, 1933 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Item 3: Cotton: The T.U.C. Plan of Socialisation, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Item 4: Democracy or Disruption? An Examination of Communist Influences in the Trade Unions, 1928 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Item 5: How Labour Will Save Agriculture, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Item 6: Industrial Negotiations and Agreements (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Author: J. R. Clynes
  - Item 7: The Tolpuddle Martyrs: How the TUC Will Commemorate the Dorsetshire Labourers Centenary, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Item 8: The Tolpuddle Martyrs: How the TUC Will Commemorate the Dorsetshire Labourers Centenary, 1934 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Item 9: Trade Union Administration, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    Author: A. W. Petch
    Notes: TUC Summer School Pamphlet 4.
- Wages (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Item 1: Bedaux: The TUC Examines the Bedaux System of Payment by Results (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Item 2: The Fair Wages Clause (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Item 3: Family Allowances: Majority and Minority Reports, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Item 4: Family Allowances: Majority and Minority Reports, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Notes: Includes discussion
  - Item 5: Holidays With Pay: The TUC Policy, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Item 6: Low Pay: TUC General Council Discussion Document, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Author: Victor Feather
  - Item 7: A Policy for Real Wages, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Item 8: Wage Fixing, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    Author: Arthur Pugh
    Notes: TUC Summer School Pamphlet 3.